<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE terms SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/writerside/1.0/glossary.dtd">
<terms>
    <term name="OIDC">
        OpenID Connect, a simple identity layer on top of the OAuth 2.0 protocol; used for SSO, authentication, and authorisation.
    </term>
    <term name="FAIR">
        Findable, Accessible, Interoperable, and Reusable; a set of principles to make data more reusable.
    </term>
    <term name="ORDO">
        Orphanet Rare Disease Ontology, an ontology for rare diseases.
    </term>
    <term name="SNOMED">
        Systematized Nomenclature of Medicine Clinical Terms, a clinical terminology system.
    </term>
    <term name="HPO">
        Human Phenotype Ontology, a standardized vocabulary of phenotypic abnormalities.
    </term>
    <term name="OMIM">
        Online Mendelian Inheritance in Man, a comprehensive compendium of human genes and genetic phenotypes.
    </term>
    <term name="NCIT">
        National Cancer Institute Thesaurus, a reference terminology for cancer research.
    </term>
    <term name="HGNC">
        HUGO Gene Nomenclature Committee, a committee that assigns standardised nomenclature to human genes.
    </term>
    <term name="BEACON">
        Beacon v2 is a protocol and specification established by the GA4GH that defines an open standard for the discovery of genomic (and phenoclinic) data in biomedical research and clinical applications.
    </term>
    <term name="GA4GH">
        Global Alliance for Genomics and Health, an international coalition that aims to enable the sharing of genomic and clinical data.
    </term>
    <term name="Nexus">
        Sonatype Nexus, a repository manager that allows you to proxy, collect, and manage dependencies, files and other artifacts.
    </term>
    <term name="KeyCloak">
        An open-source identity and access management solution.
    </term>
    <term name="Vault">
        HashiCorp Vault, a tool for managing secrets and protecting sensitive data.
    </term>
    <term name="PEM">
        PEM format, a base64-encoded format for storing and transferring cryptographic keys.
    </term>
    <term name="JWK">
        JSON Web Key, a JSON object that represents a cryptographic key.
    </term>
    <term name="JWKS">
        JSON Web Key Set, a JSON object that represents a set of JSON Web Keys.
    </term>
    <term name="realm">
        A realm is a domain of users that share the same identity, authentication, and authorisation policies.
    </term>
    <term name="KV Engine">
        Key-Value Engine, a storage engine that stores key-value pairs.
    </term>
    <term name="Molgenis">
        A platform for scientific data management. It specialises in versatile data management and database solutions.
    </term>
    <term name="Granularity Request">

    </term>
    <term name="HOOM model">

    </term>
    <term name="UUID4">
        UUID4 is a 128-bit identifier, randomly generated and represented as a 32-character hexadecimal string in the format xxxxxxxx-xxxx-4xxx-yxxx-xxxxxxxxxxxx.
    </term>
</terms>